Hi!
I'm Dr. Eric Sayer from Sayer Family Chiropractic.
In this segment, we're going to be talking about ice to treat strained backs.
Definitely just ice for 20 minutes, take an hour off.
It's very simple.
You place it on the injured area.
Don't leave it too long, otherwise you're cause other types of problems.
The other thing is after is that after any type of strain, you want to be icing for the first 48 hours.
Don't go directly to heat.
You'll cause other problems.
Ice for the first 48 hours.
20 minutes on and an hour off.
It's common also to go to heat after the first 48 hours.
Stay with ice pretty strictly for the first 48 hours.
After that, a combination treatment works very well.
20 minutes of ice, 20 minutes of heat, and then take an hour off.
The way I explain is it's just a way to shock the body into healing that part of itself faster.
The heat also is a way to bring new blood and nutrition to the area so it helps the person heal, but not during the first 48 hours.